G. Bromley Oxnam Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
G. Bromley Oxnam Papers 1823-1963 1912-1960
MSS35329
Oxnam, G. Bromley (Garfield Bromley), 1891-1963
16,000 items
137 containers
54.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Methodist clergyman and theologian. Diaries, correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and miscellaneous material documenting Oxnam's life and work as a clergyman, stance on church-state issues, and controversies relating to Catholicism, anti-communism, and other issues of faith and politics.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Athēnagoras I, Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople, 1886-1972--Correspondence.; Brown, George Smith--Correspondence.; Cavert, Samuel McCrea, 1888-1976--Correspondence.; Connelly, Matthew J., 1907-1976--Correspondence.; Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977--Correspondence.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959--Correspondence.; Eddy, Sherwood, 1871-1963--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Fry, Franklin Clark, 1900-1968--Correspondence.; Harris, Frederick Brown, 1883-1970--Correspondence.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955--Correspondence.; Jackson, Donald Lester, 1910-1981--Correspondence.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981--Correspondence.; McIntire, Carl, 1906-2002--Correspondence.; McIntyre, Marvin Hunter, 1878-1943--Correspondence.; Newton, Louie D. (Louie Devotie), 1892-1986--Correspondence.; Oxnam, G. Bromley (Garfield Bromley), 1891-1963.; Parlin, Charles C. (Charles Coolidge), 1898- --Correspondence.; Poling, Daniel A. (Daniel Alfred), 1884-1968--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Sherrill, Henry Knox, 1890-1980--Correspondence.; Stidger, William L. (William Le Roy), 1886- --Correspondence.; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950--Correspondence.; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.; Velde, Harold Himmel, 1910-1985--Correspondence.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965--Correspondence.; Welch, Herbert, 1862-1969--Correspondence.
Organizations
Catholic Church--Foreign relations--United States.; Catholic Church--Relations--Protestant churches.; Church of All Nations (New York, N.Y.); United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.
Subjects
Church and state.; Methodist Church--United States.; Protestant churches--Relations--Catholic Church.
Places
United States--Foreign relations--Catholic Church.
Occupations
Clergy.; Theologians.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Bishop G. Bromley Oxnam, Methodist clergyman and theologian, were given to the Library of Congress in 1963-1964 by his wife, Ruth Fisher Oxnam.
Additional Guides
A note concerning the acquisition of the Oxnam Papers as well as a description of the material appears in the Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress (July 1964).
Access and Restrictions
The papers of G. Bromley Oxnam are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1891, Aug. 14 Born, Sonora, Calif.
1913 A.B., University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Calif.
1914 Married Ruth Fisher (died 1975)
1915 S.T.B., Boston University, Boston, Mass.
1916 Ordained Methodist minister
1916 1917 Pastor, Poplar Methodist Church, Popular, Calif.
1917 1927 Founder, pastor, and director, Church of All Nations, Los Angeles, Calif.
1919 1923 Professor of social ethics, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Calif.
1926 Member, American Delegation to Russia
1927 1928 Professor of practical theology, School of Theology, Boston University, Boston, Mass.
1928 1932 Secretary, World Peace Commission of the Methodist-Episcopal Church
1928 1936 President, DePauw University, Greencastle, Ind.
1936 Elected bishop, Methodist Episcopal Church
1936 1939 Bishop, Methodist Church, Omaha Area, Omaha, Neb.
1939 1944 Bishop, Methodist Church, Boston Area, Boston, Mass.
1939 1944 Chairman, Division of Educational Institutions, Board of Education of the Methodist Church
1940 1948 Chairman, Committee on Public Information of the Methodist Church
1940 1956 Secretary, Council of Bishops of the Methodist Church
1942 1945 Served on National War Labor Board as a special mediator in labor disputes
1942 1945 Member, Civilian Advisory Committee to the Secretary of the Navy
1944 1946 President, Federal Council of Churches
1944 1952 Bishop, Methodist Church, New York City Area, New York, N.Y.
1944 1952 President, Division of Foreign Missions, Board of Missions of the Methodist Church
1945 Chairman, Commission to Study Postwar Relief Conditions in Germany
1945 Official visitor for the Joint Chiefs of Staff to army and navy chaplains, Mediterranean Theater of Operations
1946 1948 Member, President's Committee on Higher Education
1948 1954 One of the presidents of the World Council of Churches
1952 1960 Bishop, Methodist Church, Washington, D.C., Area, Washington, D.C.
1958 President, Methodist Council of Bishops
1963, Mar. 13 Died, White Plains, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Garfield Bromley Oxnam (1891-1963) consist of diaries, correspondence, subject files, writings, addresses, sermons, lectures, notebooks, scrapbooks, daily records, and related material documenting the span of Bishop Oxnam's long career of religious and public service. The material extends from 1823 to 1963, with the bulk of the papers falling within the period 1912-1960. The collection is organized into eight series: Diaries and Journals; General Correspondence; Subject File; Speech, Article and Book File; Addresses, Lectures, and Sermons; Notes, Miscellaneous Papers, Records, and Reports; Miscellany; and Scrapbooks.
The diaries, subject files, and writings constitute the most important parts of the collection. Extensive and voluminous, the diaries are supplemented by correspondence, newspaper clippings, programs, church bulletins, photographs, articles, book reviews, addresses, sermons, lectures, notes, memoranda, reports, and records. Although there are no diaries for 1922, 1924, 1925, 1927, and 1932, entries for these years are contained in miscellaneous volumes at the end of the series. The diary entries for 1961-1963 are sketchy and sparse.
The Subject File series covers Oxnam's role in controversies over diplomatic relations between the United States and the Vatican, his participation in the issue of church and state and Protestantism as it related to Catholicism, the charges made against him of un-Americanism, his work with the Church of All Nations in Los Angeles, academic career, and other subjects closely related to Oxnam's life.
The Scrapbooks series presents in great detail Oxnam's life as reported by the press. He was involved in public as well as religious affairs, and his activities and views generated considerable publicity, which is reflected in the Scrapbooks.
Prominent or frequent correspondents include Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople Athēnagoras I, George Smith Brown, Samuel McCrea Cavert, Matthew J. Connelly, Henry Hitt Crane, John Foster Dulles, Sherwood Eddy, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Franklin Clark Fry, Frederick Brown Harris, Cordell Hull, Donald Lester Jackson, David Eli Lilienthal, Marvin Hunter McIntyre, Carl McIntire, Louie D. Newton, Charles C. Parlin, Daniel A. Polling, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin Roosevelt, Henry Knox Sherrill, William L. Stidger, Henry L. Stimson, Myron Charles Taylor, Harry S. Truman, Harold Himmel Velde, Henry A. Wallace, and Herbert Welch. There is also considerable correspondence from the general public, most of it in the Subject File.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in eight series:
Diaries and Journals, 1903-1963
General Correspondence, 1914-1963
Subject File, 1912-1962
Speech, Article, and Book File, 1913-1960
Addresses, Lectures, and Sermons, 1914-1960
Notes, Miscellaneous Papers, Records and Reports, 1895-1960
Miscellany, 1823-1963
Scrapbooks, 1912-1960
Container List
- Diaries and Journals, 1903-1963 (Box 1-32)
  Fifty-nine volumes and several folders of loose pages containing lengthy daily entries, correspondence, printed matter, programs, church bulletins, newspaper clippings, photographs, articles, book reviews, addresses, sermons, lectures, notes, memoranda, reports, and records.
  Chronologically arranged.
  - 1913-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1916-1918 (Box 2)
  - 1918-1921 (Box 3)
  - 1921-1931 (Box 4)
  - 1931-1934 (Box 5)
  - 1934-1937 (Box 6)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 11)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - 1945, Jan.-May (Box 13)
  - 1945, June-Dec. (Box 14)
  - 1946 (Box 15)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 16)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 17)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 18)
  - 1949-1950. (Box 19)
  - 1951 (Box 20)
  - 1952 (Box 21)
  - 1953 (Box 22)
  - 1953-1954, Jan.-Aug. (Box 23)
  - 1954, Sept.-1955, Dec. (Box 24)
  - 1955 (Box 25)
  - 1956 (Box 26)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 27)
  - 1958 (Box 28)
  - 1959 (Box 29)
  - 1960 (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - 1903-1960
    - 1912-1963 (Box 32)
- General Correspondence, 1914-1963 (Box 33-37)
  Letters sent and received.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization and chronologically thereunder.
  - Russell Alexander, 1935-1938 (Box 33)
  - Athēnagoras I, Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople, 1951-1962
  - George Smith Brown, 1935-1958
  - Budapest Reformed Theological Academy, Budapest, Hungary (Bishop Bereczky, etc.), 1955
  - S. Parkes Cadman, 1927-1928
  - Chiang Kai-Shek, 1958
  - Eli P. Clark, 1930
  - Henry Hitt Crane, 1932-1939
  - E. Guy Cutshall, 1932-1939
  - Andor dePaal, 1949-1950 (Box 34)
  - John Foster Dulles, 1941-1959
  - Sherwood Eddy, 1918-1959
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1945-1960
  - Frank C. Evans, 1937-1945
  - Geoffrey Fisher, 1955-1958
  - G. Hans Grueninger, 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Hermann Hagedorn, 1946- 1957
  - Lord Halifax
  - William D. Hassett, 1945-1950
  - Maurice Hindus, 1931
  - Frank E. Hines, 1932-1933
  - J. Edgar Hoover, 1938, 1947
  - Lynn Harold Hough, 1928
  - Cordell Hull, 1934-1944
  - Jesse H. Jones, 1943-1944
  - James R. Joy, 1938-1948
  - Frank Knox, 1943
  - Albert C. Knudson, 1926-1927
  - Lahey Clinic, 1943-1959
  - Adna Wright Leonard, 1919-1934
  - David Eli Lilienthall, 1940-1962
  - Henry B. Longden, 1935-1944
  - Henry Robinson Luce, 1945-1950
  - John W. McCormack, 1959
  - Robert G. McCutchan, 1936-1958
  - William F. McDowell, 1928-1937
  - Marvin Hunter McIntyre, 1941-1943
  - R. Tait McKenzie, 1935
  - Paul V. McNutt, 1941-1943
  - Felix M. McWhirter, 1928-1936
  - Daniel L. Marsh, 1935-1951 (Box 36)
  - John Masefield, 1937, undated
  - John R. Mott
  - Louie D. Newton, 1946-1953
  - William H. Cardinal O'Connell, 1943-1944
  - Norman Vincent Peale, 1954-1956
  - Kathryn Peck, 1938-1941
  - Frances Perkins, 1941-1944
  - Milo Perkins, 1943
  - Daniel A. Poling, 1938-1960
  - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1945-1950
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1952
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt and Eleanor Roosevelt, 1941-1950
  - Margaret Sanger, 1950
  - Sasamori, 1937-1947
  - Walter John Sherman, 1939-1942
  - Francis Cardinal Spellman, 1946-1947
  - John R. Steelman, 1943, 1951
  - William L. Stidger, 1939-1949
  - Henry L. Stimson, 1943-1945
  - William E. Sweet, 1939-1941
  - Texas (Southwest Texas Conference), 1953
  - Myron C. Taylor, 1945-1950
  - Harry S. Truman, 1945-1951
  - Henry A. Wallace, 1943-1946 (Box 37)
  - Henry F. Ward, 1828-1929
  - Earl Warren, 1954-1955
  - Herbert Welch, 1953-1961
  - Princess Wilhelmina, 1954, 1957
  - Charles E. Wilson, 1955
  - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1914-1963
  - Unknown, 1929, 1963
- Subject File, 1912-1962 (Box 38-70)
  Correspondence, journals, reports, records, memoranda, articles, book reviews, addresses, sermons, lectures, notes, printed matter, scrapbooks, programs, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
  Arranged by subject and by specific topic thereunder. A file of miscellaneous subject file is arranged alphabetically.
  - Un-American Activities and Related Material Correspondents include Clyde Boyle, Herbert Brownell, Dorothea Cable Cary, Kit Clardy, Jerome Davis, Charles Wesley Flint, Donald Lester Jackson, Verne P. Kaub, Corliss Lamont, Kenneth Leslie, Harvey M. Matusow, J. Howard McGrath, Carl McIntire, Louis B. Nichols, Charles C. Parlin, Alan Reitman, Robert Gilman Smith, Dirk J. Struik, Harold Himmel Velde, and John S. Wood (Box 38)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAAC)
      - 1946-1955
      - Kit Clardy File
      - Donald Lester Jackson File
      - Harold Himmel Velde File
      - Correspondence with HUAAC Members
      - Margaret Forsyth and Dorothy McConnell File
      - Carl Harvey Jackins File
      - Donald G. Lothrop File
      - Exhibits
      - Editorials and Resolutions
      - Editorials (Box 39)
      - Final Exhibit
      - General File
      - Newspaper Clippings
      - Jackson Debate, American Forum of the Air
      - Oxnam Exhibits
      - National Council of Churches' response to Rep. Jackson's attacks
      - Post-Hearing ( July 21, 1953 ) Opinion of HUAAC Committeemen
      - Harold Himmel Velde Press Release
      - Proposals for reform of HUAAC
      - Publications of HUAAC
      - Releases regarding Oxnam (Box 40)
      - Scholarly or Legal Studies
      - Public Correspondence
      - Public Correspondence (Box 41)
      - Miscellaneous Evidence
      - Miscellany
    - Hearing, July 21, 1953 (Box 42)
      - Correspondence
      - Statement to HUAAC
      - Documentation for Statement
      - Material
      - Printed Transcript of Hearing
      - Mimeographed Transcript of Hearing (Box 43)
      - Printed Matter
      - Newspapers
      - Index to Newspaper Headlines
      - Miscellany
      - Radio Reports
      - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings (Box 44)
    - Personalities, 1944-1958 (Box 45)
      - Louis Budenz
      - Edgar C. Bundy
      - D. B. Cooper
      - John T. Flynn
      - Stephen H. Fritchman
      - Ralph W. Gwinn
      - Philip S. Harper
      - Mrs. Douglas Horton
      - E. Stanley Jones
      - Verne P. Kaub
      - Owen Lattimore
      - Kenneth Leslie
      - Fulton J. Lewis, Jr.
      - Carl McIntire
      - Joe McCarthy
      - J. B. Matthews (Box 46)
      - Louis B. Nichols
      - Charles C. Parlin
      - Daniel A. Poling
      - Herbert A. Philbrick
      - Bishop Bernard J. Shell
      - Robert Gilman Smith
    - Funds, Organizations, Publications, 1934-1959 (Box 47)
      - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals
      - American Civil Liberties Union
      - American Committee for Spanish Freedom
      - American Committee for Yugoslav Relief
      - American Council of Christian Churches
      - American Council of Christian Laymen (Verne P. Kaub)
      - American Mercury (Box 48)
      - The American Nationalist
      - American Round Table on India
      - American-Russian Institute
      - American-Soviet Friendship; National Council and Massachusetts Council
      - Christian Beacon
      - Civil Rights Congress
      - Classmate
      - Committee for Constitutional Government (Edward A. Rumely, et al.)
      - Constitutional Protective League
      - Council of Bishops on Methodist Federation for Social Action
      - Council of Bishops regarding Committee on Un-American Activities
      - Fellowships for Reconciliation
      - Free Chinese Literature Campaign
      - Friends of the Spanish Republic
      - Fund for the Republic
      - Hoosier Legionnaire
      - Iron Curtain Refugee Campaign
      - The Knoxville Journal
      - Methodist Federation for Social Action (Box 49)
      - Methodist Information
      - Militant Truth
      - Nashville Banner
      - National Committee for Strengthening Congress
      - National Council of Churches
      - National Laymen's Council
      - The Protestant
      - Sons of the American Revolution
      - Soviet Russia Today
      - United Neighborhood Houses
      - Washington Post
      - World Council of Churches
  - Un-American Activities and Related Material (Box 50)
    - Articles and Books, 1927-1955
      - Oxnam's books
      - Behind Soviet Power by Jerome Davis
      - “Methodism's Pink Fringe” by Stanley High, (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 51)
      - “The Problem of the Ex-Communist” by Sidney Hook
      - The Road Ahead by John T. Flynn, (4 folders)
      - “To Make Our System Secure” by Vannevar Bush
      - “Communism and the Protestant Clergy” by J. B. Matthews, Reinhold Niebuhr and Oxnam
    - Miscellaneous Files and Subjects, 1926-1960 (Box 52)
      - American Broadcasting Co. (Paul Harvey)
      - Attacks on Education
      - Attacks on Federal and National Council of Churches
      - Willis Ballinger (Station WPIK)
      - Boston University; Boston, Mass., President Case, Professor Halpern, and Whittaker Chambers
      - Herbert Brownell and J. Edgar Hoover
      - Bureau County Republican (M. E. Take)
      - Case for Freedom
      - Case Studies in Personnel Security
      - Christian Church and Communism
      - Communism
      - Department of Justice (Box 53)
        - Communists as Witnesses
        - Southern Conference Educational Fund
      - Fellowship of Reconciliation
      - General Miscellany
      - Investigating Committees (Box 54)
      - Philharmonic Auditorium, Los Angeles, Calif., Incident
      - “Protestantism Answers Hate”
      - “Radical Charges”
      - “The Red Network”
      - Radio and Television
      - Santa Monica Attacks
      - Security Procedures
    - Harvey M. Matusow File, 1945-1955 (Box 55)
    - Printed Matter, 1922-1957
  - Church of All Nations, 1912-1940 (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1917-1927
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Records, 1917-1927, (1 vol.) (Box 57)
    - Records, 1910-1922
    - Boy's Work, 1939-1940 (Box 58)
    - Miscellany and Printed Matter, 1919-1939
    - Photographs, 1917-1927
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Records, 1917-1927
    - Letter of Commendation, 1926-1934 (Box 59)
    - Worker's College, 1922
    - City Parish, 1924, (3 vols.)
    - Building Plans, undated
    - Financial Records, 1912-1924
    - Parish Records, 1919-1921
  - Diplomatic Relations with the Vatican, 1939-1954 Correspondents include Eugene Carson Blake, Samuel McCrea Cavert, Matthew J. Connelly, Franklin Clark Fry, Frederick Brown Harris, B. R. Lacy, Jr., Henry F. Schuk, Henry Knox Sherrill, Roy H. Short, and Myron C. Taylor (Box 60)
    - Roman Catholic-Protestant Relations
    - Mark Clark Appointment
    - Correspondence from Ministers
    - General Correspondence, (1 folder) (Box 61)
    - Myron C. Taylor and World Council of Churches
    - Myron C. Taylor
    - National Council of Churches; Coordinating Committee; United States Diplomatic Relations with Vatican
    - Correspondence with President Harry S. Truman
    - Federal Council of Churches (opinions of diplomatic relations), (1 folder) (Box 62)
    - Press Releases
    - General
  - Catholicism and Protestantism, 1939-1952 (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1913-1962, 1939-1952 (Box 64)
    - Addresses, DePauw Alumni Club, by W. P. Evans, 1931
    - Better America Federation, 1922-1931
    - Boston University School of Theology, Boston, Mass.
      - Personal Record, 1913-1915
      - Class Rolls, 1927-1928
      - General, 1938-1939
    - Christian Church and the Responsible Society, 1944-1955
    - Charges, Colonel LeRoy Smith and related papers, 1923-1931
    - Church Union, 1920-1955, (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 65)
    - Churches and Air Manual Issue, 1960
    - Committee for Preservation of Methodism, 1952-1953
    - Democracy and Totalitarianism, 1936-1941
    - John Foster Dulles, 1946-1948
    - Sherwood Eddy, 1931-1942 (Box 66)
    - Fascism, 1924-1941
    - Gandhi, Mahatma, 1923-1948
    - Garrett Labor Thesis, 1928, 1958-1960
    - Grace Church of Wilmington, Delaware, 1952-1953
    - Inter-Church World Movement of North America, 1920
    - Jurisdictional System, 1957
    - Kemal Ataturk, 1922-1938
    - Kresge Foundation, 1958-1959
    - Labor, Arbitration Decisions, 1941-1942
    - League for Organization of Progress, 1931 (Box 67)
    - David Eli Lilienthal, 1938-1949
    - Edwin Markham, 1924, 1932
    - Methodist Commission on Camp Activities, 1955-1946
    - Methodist Conferences
      - Programs, 1948-1960
      - Baltimore-Washington Conference, 1953-1954
      - Peninsula Conference, 1956-1958 (Box 68)
      - General Conference, 1923
      - General Conference, 1936
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1942-1956
    - Benito Mussolini, 1913, 1928, 1936
    - National Council of Christians and Jews, 1944-1951 (Box 69)
    - United Auto Workers; Public Review Board, 1957-1962
    - World Council of Churches, 1948-1955, (2 folders); (11 folders) (Box 70)
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1913-1960 (Box 71-82)
  Drafts, typescripts and printed copies of articles, book reviews, typescripts of books and seminar papers, miscellaneous outlines, and related material.
  Arranged by type of material and chronologically thereunder.
  - Article File, 1918-1960 (Box 71)
    - Bound
      - The Modern Samaritan of the Church of All Nations, 1922-1923
      - In Days to Come, 1922-1923
      - Miscellaneous Articles
      - Articles and Book Reviews (Box 72)
        - 1929-1941
        - 1941-1947 (Box 73)
        - 1943-1954 (Box 74)
        - 1946-1960 (Box 75)
      - Today and Tomorrow in the Omaha Area, 1936-1937
      - Facing Facts, 1935-1937
    - Unbound (Box 76)
      - 1918-1943
      - 1944-1948 (Box 77)
      - 1949-1951 (Box 78)
      - 1952-1958 (Box 79)
      - Undated, (6 folders)
  - Book File, 1927-1958 (Box 80)
    - The Church and Contemporary Change, 1950
    - On This Rock, 1951
    - The Christian's Vocation, 1943
    - Preaching in a Revolutionary Age, 1944
    - Labor and Tomorrow's World, 1945
    - Testament of Faith, 1958
    - Behold Thy Mother, 1944 (Box 81)
    - Facing the Future Un-Afraid, circa 1944
    - Ethical Ideals of Jesus, 1941
    - By This Sign Conquer, 1942
    - Russian Impressions, 1927
    - Youth and New America, 1928
    - Personalities in Social Reform, 1950
    - Atlantic Monthly Press Chapter on Church Union, 1949-1950
    - Christian Church and the State, undated
    - Catholicism, undated, (5 folders)
  - Miscellany, 1913-1955 (Box 82)
    - “The Franciscans in California” (Seminar Paper), 1915
    - Miscellaneous Outlines, 1913-1921
    - Press Release, 1955
    - Conversation with Henry Hitt Crane, 1955
    - “Is Peace a Realizable Ideal”, undated
- Addresses, Lectures, and Sermons, 1914-1960 (Box 83-99)
  Bound and unbound outlines, drafts, typescripts, and printed copies.
  - Bound (Box 83)
    - Summaries of Addresses
      - 1930-1936
      - 1919-1942 (Box 84)
      - 1942-1947 (Box 85)
      - 1947-1952 (Box 86)
      - 1948-1955 (Box 87)
      - 1953-1960 (Box 88)
    - Methodist Radio Hour, 1938-1939 (Box 89)
    - Radio Meditations, 1953 (Box 90)
    - Radio Addresses, 1934-1935
    - National Vespers, 1946-1948
  - Unbound (Box 91)
    - 1922-1944
    - 1945-1947 (Box 92)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 93)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 94)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 95)
    - Undated (Box 96)
  - Outlines and Material, 1914-1958 (Box 97-99)
  - Lecture Records, 1923-1960 (Box 100)
- Notes, Miscellaneous Papers, Records and Reports, 1895-1960 (Box 101-109)
  Bound and unbound.
  Grouped by type of material.
  - Notes and Papers, 1895-1958 (Box 101)
    - Philosophy, 1914
    - Miscellaneous Book Notes and Papers, 1914-1915